# **Peter Rosser**

peter@peterrosser.com +44 (0) 7521 686243 Flat 1 120 Dalberg Road SW2 1AP London

#### **Profile**

I am a contract full-stack Software Engineer, comfortable working in both Unix and Windows environments. I've been coding professionally since 2011, and as a hobby for the decade prior. My passion is high-volume transactional systems, data analytics, and automation. I've focused on Database & Site Reliability, Performance Tuning, and Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment. My experience is mostly financial, working on accounting, expense tracking, banking, and trading systems.

The languages I am most familiar with are Golang, SQL, C#, VB, and XSLT. I've also written small scripts and debugged problems in half a dozen other languages.

I am active in my local user groups and developer communities, and enjoy competing in hackathons and start-up weekends. Samples of my work and projects are available on <u>GitHub</u>, or by request. Where allowed, I prefer to share & open source my work.

I speak English natively, have a New Zealand passport and a United Kingdom work visa.

# **Employment**

#### February 2017 NDA

Contract Software Developer – designed, developed, and deployed a Twitter datamining application, providing UK tweet location & photo data in various forms for an advertising campaign. Experience with Golang, MySQL, Bash.

# July 2016 - Current Rosser Software

Director

# April 2015 – August 2016 Pershing, a BNY Mellon Company

Lead Developer - I worked on Front Office order processing software. We maintained trading platforms for automated and manual trading of funds & equities across the UK & Europe. I have been involved with upgrading our services and introducing scaling and resiliency to increase our performance & throughput of orders. I worked with 3<sup>rd</sup> party vendors to integrate and manage their services with our software. I triaged potential missed orders for trading teams if there are system outages. This was on a globally distributed team.

Experience with the full .NET stack; C#, Visual Basic, SQL Server, PowerShell, IBM MQ.

#### March 2013 – January 2015 Spendvision

Software Developer - I gather client requirements and then code the modules which output transaction data into formats required for enterprise software. I write and test custom scripts and

procedures which change or report on our databases. I'm also involved in fixing bugs and applying changes to existing reports, and performing triage/analysis and managing the workflow queue. I have been involved with adding features and maintaining our internal tools. The development teams followed an Agile Scrum process, and I used TDD design patterns where possible.

Experience with the full .NET stack; ASP.NET C#, MVVM, SQL Server, XSLT, XML, and JavaScript.

# March 2012 – February 2013 Attaché Software

Contract Software Developer - I designed, developed and tested features & reports for our Attaché PRO software. This is accounting and business management software which is tailored for the client's requirements. I have been involved in writing 80% of our dashboards feature using XML & SQL, creating custom reporting modules as per client's requests, and providing legacy support and debugging for our existing suite of software. I also maintain the various internal customer care & billing software for Attaché Software.

Experience with Delphi, Visual Basic, XML, and a variant of NoSQL.

# 2003 - 2009 Lakes Golf Course

I have worked on developing the website and keeping the client database organised, as well as general IT support for a range of specialised equipment and computers. I have also been involved with the outdoor maintenance and projects, and serving in the Café and Pro shop. Outside, I was often given a simple brief, and had to create a plan to develop an area of the course, using my own creativity and limited resources. Inside, I dealt with a range of customers and their requests, and was entrusted with end of day closing, balancing tills and banking cash.

Experience with Microsoft Access, HTML, and networking/hardware administration.

# Qualifications

# **Bachelor of Science Majoring in Computer Science (BSc)**

2011 University of Auckland

Focused on Mathematics and Software Development, with interest papers in Philosophy, Spanish, Economics and Accounting.

Experienced in Java & C#, C, MySQL, and Ubuntu

Limited Experience in x86 Assembly, CUDA, HTML, XML & Shell Scripting.

# National Diploma of Quantity Surveying (NDQS)

2011 UNITEC New Zealand

Completed full time at night school, while concurrently studying at the University of Auckland for my science degree. Focused on Project & Contract Management, Estimation, and Measurement.

#### A Bursary and University Entrance

2003 Senior College of New Zealand

#### Volunteer Work

# 2000 - 2011 Children's Bible Ministries Camp Leader

Children's Bible Ministries runs school holiday camps for disadvantaged children between the ages of 7-13 Since I turned 14 I have been involved first as a junior leader and then as an adult leader, leading a group of 8-12 children for the week. I have learnt valuable leadership and time management skills, and how to relate with people from very different backgrounds.

# 2006 - 2011 Parachute Music Festival Volunteer Crew

I volunteered to help set-up during the week prior to the festival. This has involved setting up the village (stalls, food vendors, the giant café, seating areas, merchandise tent) and delivering hired equipment to the various other crews. The crew is between 20-25 people, and in the last few years I have been delegated to lead a team of 5-6 others around the site, getting various tasks completed.

# References available on request